<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recents Article on MarkCite Blog</title><link>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Recents Article on MarkCite Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 17:06:57 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.markcite.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Statistical Analysis With SPSS</title><link>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/statistics/statistical-analysis-with-spss/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 17:06:57 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/statistics/statistical-analysis-with-spss/</guid><description>SPSS is one of the leading tools for statistical analysis. Here we shall learn some of the methods of doing common statistical analysis with SPSS.
How To Do Fisher Exact Test in SPSS Data type Two categorical variables. Steps Click Analyze -&amp;gt; Descriptive Statistics -&amp;gt; Crosstabs... Drag and drop (at least) one variable into the Row(s) and one in Column(s) box. Click on Exact, and then select Exact bullet option.</description></item><item><title>How to Install Wordpress On Localhost</title><link>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/wordpress/how-to-install-wordpress-localhost-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 23:41:09 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/wordpress/how-to-install-wordpress-localhost-2/</guid><description>In this tutorial, we shall discuss how you can install Wordpress in your local server. In this post, I assume that you already have a local server set up using XAMPP or Devilbox. Click here if you want to see how to set up Devilbox in your mac.
Download the Wordpress latest version First you need to download the latest version of Wordpress. Go the this link to download the latest ZIP folder.</description></item><item><title>Xampp Alternative in Mac for Mysql: Devilbox</title><link>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/mysql/xampp-alternative-in-mac-for-mysql/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 18:53:47 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/mysql/xampp-alternative-in-mac-for-mysql/</guid><description>For a very long time, I have been using XAMPP as my local environment to create applications. XAMPP uses MariaDB which is almost similar to MySQL but here is the catch, almost. It came to my notice when I started to work with JSON. MariaDB had announced that it would provide the support for JSON in their official blog back in 2019. But as off 2021, still they haven&amp;rsquo;t added the JSON support completely, instead try to go through the route by converting JSON column into longtext which doesn&amp;rsquo;t deliver the full capability of JSON.</description></item><item><title>How to Download Protected File From Google Drive</title><link>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/tutorials/how-to-download-protected-file-from-google-drive/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 12:30:24 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/tutorials/how-to-download-protected-file-from-google-drive/</guid><description>Warning This is solely for educational purposes.
My use case My wife wanted to enroll in an online course, but the deadline had passed. When she contacted the center, they informed her that they had recorded classes from the previous two days, and that she could join and catch up with the current batch if she so desired. However, they usually delete the recorded videos within 7 days. However, we decided to enroll in the course, but discovered that the watch hours of the recorded classes were too many to cover in a few days, and the files were protected, so there was no way to download and watch them later.</description></item><item><title>MySql Tips and Tricks</title><link>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/mysql/mysql-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:39:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/mysql/mysql-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description>Repairing utf8 broken characters Sometimes during data table backup or migration, you may end up having broken utf8 characters. A easy way to solve the problem is following the below SQL Query: 1 2 UPDATE table_name SET column_name = CONVERT(BINARY CONVERT(column_name USING latin1) USING utf8); That&amp;rsquo;s it. It will fix the broken characters. But as always be sure to back up your data table before doing any of such conversion.</description></item><item><title>How to add custom subdomain in GitHub Pages and Cloudflare</title><link>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/github/how-to-add-custom-subdomain-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 20:22:34 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/github/how-to-add-custom-subdomain-github-pages/</guid><description>If you are using GitHub pages for hosting your static website like this MarkCite Blog and link it to a custom subdomain using Cloudflare, this tutorial is for you.
Steps in Cloudflare Log in to your Cloudflare account and select your site. Go to the DNS settings. Click on the Add record button. Select a CNAME type, write the name of your subdomain, (for example: blog), write the GitHub link for your GitHub pages (for example: ashonko.</description></item><item><title>How to Download SlideShare Presentation as PPT</title><link>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/tutorials/how-to-download-slideshare-as-ppt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 20:01:34 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/tutorials/how-to-download-slideshare-as-ppt/</guid><description>This tutorial will show you how to download a SlideShare presentation in PPT format so that you can work on it or make changes in PowerPoint before presenting it to your audience.
About SlideShare SlideShare, which is owned by Scribd, is a website where users can share professional presentations, infographics, videos, documents, and other items. They have the option of sharing these contents privately or publicly. It is very likely that the presentation you are looking for has already been uploaded to SlideShare.</description></item><item><title>Why I Chose Hugo</title><link>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/hugo/whay-i-chose-hugo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 17:28:34 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/hugo/whay-i-chose-hugo/</guid><description>A new start My name is Rajib Biswas. And this is my first post in Hugo.
What was I thinking For the most part, I have been looking for a smart solution to get rid of all the heave load of the WordPress. For most of my years in development, I have used WordPress to create blog and other sites. But to be honest, I never liked it. The main issue was the speed.</description></item><item><title>How to load local HTML file in Flutter WebView</title><link>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/flutter/how-to-load-local-html-file-in-flutter-webview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 21:01:34 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://blog.markcite.com/blog/flutter/how-to-load-local-html-file-in-flutter-webview/</guid><description>Background! My wife joined the internship program in a Medical College Hospital yesterday. This morning she showed me a PDF file of a hand note for the treatment protocols in Obstetric Department. She said to me that do you have any better version of that?
Well, during my internship program, I wrote some treatment protocols in a word file. So I thought why not make an HTML app from these word files and pack them into a WebView of a Flutter project to make an Android app for my wife.</description></item></channel></rss>